<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>work on Portfolio - Nikola Stoyanov</title>
    <link>http://newdegeneration.xyz/work/</link>
    <description>Recent content in work on Portfolio - Nikola Stoyanov</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>av0id.biz@gmail.com (Nikola Stoyanov)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>av0id.biz@gmail.com (Nikola Stoyanov)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Nikola Soyanov, 2023</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://newdegeneration.xyz/work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Postcards and Contraband</title>
      <link>http://newdegeneration.xyz/work/cards/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>av0id.biz@gmail.com (Nikola Stoyanov)</author>
      <guid>http://newdegeneration.xyz/work/cards/</guid>
      <description>„Картички и контрабанда“ започва от изследването на служебен архив от агенция „Митници“, дирекция „Борба с наркотрафика“ от периода 1975-1985. Намерените служебни бележки, фотографии, негативи, справки и докладни записки маркират част от рутината на митническото дело, като проверка и регулация на транзита, но също и дипломатическия образ, който митниците трябва да поддържат пред международната общност.
Водещо тук е съмнението, че намерените архиви дават само частичен поглед към организирания „скрит транзит“ - термин, зад който комунистическото управление на Народна република България прикрива контрабандата търговия, осъществявана от Държавна сигурност чрез търговски предприятия и организации.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nature Morte</title>
      <link>http://newdegeneration.xyz/work/nature-morte/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>av0id.biz@gmail.com (Nikola Stoyanov)</author>
      <guid>http://newdegeneration.xyz/work/nature-morte/</guid>
      <description>NATURE MORTE is a multimediaproject that plants the philosophical question in the ground - on a part of the country’s criticalinfrastructure, where access is highly restricted. In an attempt to find different approaches to reach the excavation and its visualization, open data from satellite and geological surveys and measurements were used, through which the digital topography of the mines was built.
Although the cosmic time of geoformation - the million-year superimposition of layers that proceeds in relative calm, where separate elements barely interact, there are also short periods of ruptures recorded in the layers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Destructive Sensuality</title>
      <link>http://newdegeneration.xyz/work/destructive-sensuality/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>av0id.biz@gmail.com (Nikola Stoyanov)</author>
      <guid>http://newdegeneration.xyz/work/destructive-sensuality/</guid>
      <description>Destructive Sensuality is a video collage investigating the specifics of commercial video codec degradation. Based on key moments in Bulgaria’s visual subconscious made up of vital videos, it uses various methods of controlled im- age destruction and degradation based on structural compression in videos. Destructive Sensuality is a pop-up exhibition by Sofia Dimova and Nikola Stoyanov, where the two artists romanticize the destructive dynamics of sensual experiences that imperceptibly become part of our everyday lives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Latent Space</title>
      <link>http://newdegeneration.xyz/work/latent-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>av0id.biz@gmail.com (Nikola Stoyanov)</author>
      <guid>http://newdegeneration.xyz/work/latent-space/</guid>
      <description>Latent space is where the gaze of artificial intelligence itself draws a picturesque horizon, delving into the hidden rooms of secret research facilities, investigative organizations, classified databases. An imaginary space that the machine illuminates, exposing the postmodern subject’s built-in subversiveness of aesthetic experience in its internal mechanics, referentiality and element of incompleteness. The so-called noise in communication theory is a recognized information field defying systematization. Instead, the algorithm constructs faces, machines, corridors and cloud spaces in a process of incom- pleteness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rе:Process</title>
      <link>http://newdegeneration.xyz/work/re-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>av0id.biz@gmail.com (Nikola Stoyanov)</author>
      <guid>http://newdegeneration.xyz/work/re-process/</guid>
      <description>RE:PROCESS exhibits photographs of everyday urban objects. In the construction and deconstruction traces can be found upon the urban surface, a peculiar language, through which different modalities of appearance are formed and unfolded. Easily found but tough tо comprehend the signs, grilles, and hanging cables will be our entrance to a forgotten archive of urban fabric. What remains hidden here is the photographic eye behind the camera obscura, looking at the image-reality, in a stance not of drifting in the world but being seduced by it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grey Zone Dispositive</title>
      <link>http://newdegeneration.xyz/work/grey-zone-dispositive/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>av0id.biz@gmail.com (Nikola Stoyanov)</author>
      <guid>http://newdegeneration.xyz/work/grey-zone-dispositive/</guid>
      <description>The city - transfigured into a gray zone emptied of people, of lights, immersed under water or discarded in the wild cosmos, folded beyond practicality, it represents a capsule emptied of its nature, emptied of its structures of power, emptied of its social bodies. A dispositive without practice, without knowledge and expertise, withoout our institutions and without time - a pure assemblage. The project presents a virtual city-scape assembled out of distorted models of our familiar urban environment, rearanged into a non-euclidian vista.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>И-Икса</title>
      <link>http://newdegeneration.xyz/work/i-iksa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>av0id.biz@gmail.com (Nikola Stoyanov)</author>
      <guid>http://newdegeneration.xyz/work/i-iksa/</guid>
      <description>Настоящaта изложба е номадска по природа, водена от черното море, което е без пристан и без бряг, далеч от ясния крясък на морска птица. Злокобна прокоба, довята там, където не принадлежи – в планинското подножие. Тази предварителна бележка очертава възможната география на живописната екзистенция, отвъд конкретното пространство.
И-ИКСА е експресионистичен завой към чистата абстракция. Ход, който съхранява техничността на автора, същевременно скривайки неговия жест в завършените картини. Те биха могли да носят имена като КУЧИ БОЙ, НАРКОМАНСКА ХВАТКА, ОБСЕСИЯ, което би ги затворило в нарочно тълкуване.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In:Process</title>
      <link>http://newdegeneration.xyz/work/in-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>av0id.biz@gmail.com (Nikola Stoyanov)</author>
      <guid>http://newdegeneration.xyz/work/in-process/</guid>
      <description>The drive to capture the city as an affective totality was what led to the inception of this project. Thought, structured and imple- mented over the urban grid it draws a hyper-fiction. Its origins lie in the delirium of government documents, their leaks and their inaccessibility. Its target, the re- turn to the archive. IN:PROCESS aims to present photographs of objects from the everyday urban space. In the pro- cesses of construction and disin- tegration, marks are found on the urban surface, a kind of language through which various modalities of appearance are formed and de- veloped.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music for a New Nigh Life</title>
      <link>http://newdegeneration.xyz/work/music-for-a-new-nigh-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>av0id.biz@gmail.com (Nikola Stoyanov)</author>
      <guid>http://newdegeneration.xyz/work/music-for-a-new-nigh-life/</guid>
      <description>Music for a New Night Life deals with Mark Fishers concept of hauntology and lost futures. It vi- sually shows a cymatic matrix of a city in flux, of its dreams and night- mares and finally of its reality filled with nostalgia. The tidal feeling of turbulence wroth by the ancient currents of the Black Sea returns us to a state of Freudian unconsciousness, a downcast euphoria, somatically revealing the subject to the base nostalgia of Oedipal separation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
