<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>work on Nikola Stoyanov</title>
    <link>//192.168.5.102:8080/work/</link>
    <description>Recent content in work on Nikola Stoyanov</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 23:30:59 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//192.168.5.102:8080/work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Black Fax off the Hook</title>
      <link>//192.168.5.102:8080/work/black-fax/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 23:30:59 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//192.168.5.102:8080/work/black-fax/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Black Fax off the Hook&amp;rdquo; enacts an insurrectionary transmission—a cultural guerrilla operation leveraging the destructive power of the &amp;ldquo;black fax.&amp;rdquo; A black fax, in the narrowest terms, is a solidified swath of ink transmitted to obliterate a fax machine’s capacity, draining its resources in a direct material assault on perception itself—a tactical intervention akin to a digital denial-of-service attack. his exhibit configures black faxing as a tool of psychopolitical derision, a constantly clicking fusillade of narrative flooding the space of perception.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Postcards and Contraband</title>
      <link>//192.168.5.102:8080/work/the-first-ten/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 23:30:59 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//192.168.5.102:8080/work/the-first-ten/</guid>
      <description>The second showing of the now upgraded exhibition took place in Sofia. The exhibition had two sites: one at the Harta Gallery and another installation piece, &amp;ldquo;The First Ten&amp;rdquo; by Nikola Stoyanov, on the window display of Posta art space on one of the capital&amp;rsquo;s busiest boulevards.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Postcards and Contraband&amp;rdquo; has its inception in an incidentally found archive from the Bulgarian Customs Agency, Directorate &amp;ldquo;Struggle Against Narcotics Trafficking,&amp;rdquo; from the period 1975-1985.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>When the time comes you will understand</title>
      <link>//192.168.5.102:8080/work/youll-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//192.168.5.102:8080/work/youll-know/</guid>
      <description>The pieces uses both found and bought elemts tipical for construction that are easely bought. This is a mediation on the typical for Bulgaria DIY repair culture,, where old metal elemts that were not used for construction get repourposed for makeshift unregulated repairs.&#xA;Is an illigal destructive growth in the hearth of a city, that is always being built up and never accomodates its inhabinatnts.&#xA;The protest piece was a part of the public internation section of buna festival</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Postcards and Contraband</title>
      <link>//192.168.5.102:8080/work/cards/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 23:30:59 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//192.168.5.102:8080/work/cards/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Postcards and Contraband&amp;rdquo; begins by examining a work archive of the Bulgarian Customs Agency, Directorate for Combating Drug Trafficking from 1975-1985. The service notes, photographs, negatives, summaries and reports found mark part of the routine of the Customs Agency work, such as inspection and regulation of transit, but also the diplomatic image the Customs Agency must maintain to the international community.&#xA;The leading suspicion here is that the found archives give only a partial insight into the organized &amp;ldquo;hidden transit&amp;rdquo; - a term behind which the communist government of the People&amp;rsquo;s Republic of Bulgaria concealed the smuggling trade carried out by the State Security through commercial enterprises and organizations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nature Morte</title>
      <link>//192.168.5.102:8080/work/nature-morte/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 23:05:59 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//192.168.5.102:8080/work/nature-morte/</guid>
      <description>Nature Morte is a multimedia project that plants the philosophical question firmly into the ground - on a part of the country&amp;rsquo;s highly restricted critical infrastructure. In an attempt to find different approaches to reach the excavation and its visualization, open data from satellite and geological surveys and measurements were used, through which the digital topography of the mines has been built.&#xA;The visuals obtained from satellite images can be called operational, as a continuation of the &amp;ldquo;operational image&amp;rdquo; coined by the German director Harun Farocki, denoting &amp;ldquo;images that do not represent an object, but are part of an operation&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exemplary Home</title>
      <link>//192.168.5.102:8080/work/exemplary-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 23:30:59 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//192.168.5.102:8080/work/exemplary-home/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Death Valley</title>
      <link>//192.168.5.102:8080/work/shadow-valley/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 23:30:59 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//192.168.5.102:8080/work/shadow-valley/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Humor is the politeness of despair</title>
      <link>//192.168.5.102:8080/work/destructive-sensuality/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//192.168.5.102:8080/work/destructive-sensuality/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Humor is the politeness of despair&amp;rdquo; in a meditaion on how the demonically possed inhrent strange channel switching powers and compulsions. Technically the piece is a video collage investigating the specifics of commercial video codec degradation. Based on key moments in Bulgaria’s visual subconscious, it uses various methods of controlled image destruction and degradation based on structural compression in videos. It is part of the &amp;ldquo;Destructive Sensuality&amp;rdquo; an exhibition by Sofia Dimova and Nikola Stoyanov, where the two artists romanticize the destructive dynamics of sensual experiences that imperceptibly become part of our everyday lives.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Latent Space</title>
      <link>//192.168.5.102:8080/work/latent-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 23:15:59 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//192.168.5.102:8080/work/latent-space/</guid>
      <description>Latent space is where the gaze of artificial intelligence alone draws the picturesque horizon, delving into the hidden rooms of secret research centers, intelligence organizations, and classified databases. An imagined space that the machine illuminates, exposing the postmodern subject&amp;rsquo;s built-in subversiveness of aesthetic experience in its internal mechanics, referentiality, and element of incompleteness. The so-called noise in communication theory is a recognized information field that does not lend itself to systematization.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Re:Process</title>
      <link>//192.168.5.102:8080/work/re-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//192.168.5.102:8080/work/re-process/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;RE:PROCESS&amp;rdquo; exhibits photographs of everyday urban objects. In the construction and deconstruction traces can be found upon the urban surface, a peculiar language, through which different modalities of appearance are formed and unfolded. Easily found but tough tо comprehend the signs, grilles, and hanging cables will be our entrance to a forgotten archive of urban fabric.&#xA;What remains hidden here is the photographic eye behind the camera obscura, looking at the image-reality, in a stance not of drifting in the world but being seduced by it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grey Zone/Dispositive</title>
      <link>//192.168.5.102:8080/work/grey-zone/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 23:30:59 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//192.168.5.102:8080/work/grey-zone/</guid>
      <description>The city - transfigured into a gray zone emptied of people, of lights, immersed under water or discarded in the wild cosmos, folded beyond practicality, it represents a capsule emptied of its nature, emptied of its structures of power, emptied of its social bodies. A dispositive without practice, without knowledge and expertise, withoout our institutions and without time - a pure assemblage.&#xA;The project presents a virtual city-scape assembled out of distorted models of our familiar urban environment, rearanged into a non-euclidian vista.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Big MONUMENT of the Small Past</title>
      <link>//192.168.5.102:8080/work/monument/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 23:30:59 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//192.168.5.102:8080/work/monument/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I-Ixa</title>
      <link>//192.168.5.102:8080/work/i-ixa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 23:00:59 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//192.168.5.102:8080/work/i-ixa/</guid>
      <description>The exhibition is nomadic in nature, led by the Black Sea, which is without harbour and without shore, far from the clear squawk of a sea bird. A malevolent curse, brought where it does not belong - in the mountain foothills. This preliminary note outlines the possible geography of pictorial existence, beyond concrete space.&#xA;I-Ixa is an expressionistic turn towards pure abstraction. A move that preserves the artist&amp;rsquo;s technicality while hiding his gesture in the finished paintings.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In:Process</title>
      <link>//192.168.5.102:8080/work/in-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 23:05:59 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//192.168.5.102:8080/work/in-process/</guid>
      <description>The drive to capture the city as an affective totality was what led to the inception of this project. Thought, structured and implemented over the urban grid it draws a hyper-fiction. Its origins lie in the delirium of government documents, their leaks and their inaccessibility. Its target, the return to the archive. In:Process aims to present photographs of objects from the everyday urban space. In the processes of construction and disintegration, marks are found on the urban surface, a kind of language through which various modalities of appearance are formed and developed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Allegorical Impulse</title>
      <link>//192.168.5.102:8080/work/allegorical-impulse/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 23:30:59 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//192.168.5.102:8080/work/allegorical-impulse/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Music for a New Night Life</title>
      <link>//192.168.5.102:8080/work/music-for-a-new-nighlife/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 23:05:59 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//192.168.5.102:8080/work/music-for-a-new-nighlife/</guid>
      <description>Music for a New Night Life deals with Mark Fishers concept of hauntology and lost futures. It visually shows a cymatic matrix of a city in flux, of its dreams and nightmares and finally of its reality filled with nostalgia. The tidal feeling of turbulence wroth by the ancient currents of the Black Sea returns us to a state of Freudian unconsciousness, a downcast euphoria, somatically revealing the subject to the base nostalgia of Oedipal separation.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
