<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Collab on Nikola Stoyanov</title>
    <link>https://newdegeneration.xyz/categories/collab/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Collab on Nikola Stoyanov</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 23:30:59 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://newdegeneration.xyz/categories/collab/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Black Fax off the Hook</title>
      <link>https://newdegeneration.xyz/work/black-fax/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 23:30:59 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://newdegeneration.xyz/work/black-fax/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Black Fax off the Hook&amp;rdquo; is an insurrectionary transmission—a cultural guerrilla operation leveraging the destructive power of spam. In its most basic sense, a black fax can be defined as a malicious transmission, specifically a sheet of black print sent in rapid succession to a fax machine. This simple act overwhelms the machine’s ink and paper supply, a material assault akin to a digital denial-of-service attack, disrupting the machine’s functionality and rendering it impotent.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You’ll Understand When the Time Comes</title>
      <link>https://newdegeneration.xyz/work/youll-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://newdegeneration.xyz/work/youll-know/</guid>
      <description>As part of the Buna 2 Festival (2024), You’ll Understand when the Time Comes emerged as an urban intervention and installation, interrogating the boundaries of art, repair, and decay it navigated the murky territory between spontaneous urban repair and conspiratorial paranoia. You’ll Understand when the Time Comes an illegal destructive growth in the hearth of a city, that is always being built up and never accommodates its inhabitants. Constructed entirely from discarded, abandoned and readily available construction materials—metal brackets, fasteners, and discarded fragments—the piece embodied Bulgaria’s deeply ingrained DIY repair culture.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Postcards and Contraband</title>
      <link>https://newdegeneration.xyz/work/cards/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 23:30:59 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://newdegeneration.xyz/work/cards/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Postcards and Contraband&amp;rdquo; begins by examining a work archive of the Bulgarian Customs Agency, Directorate for Combating Drug Trafficking from 1975-1985. The service notes, photographs, negatives, summaries and reports found mark part of the routine of the Customs Agency work, such as inspection and regulation of transit, but also the diplomatic image the Customs Agency must maintain to the international community.&#xA;The leading suspicion here is that the found archives give only a partial insight into the organized &amp;ldquo;hidden transit&amp;rdquo; - a term behind which the communist government of the People&amp;rsquo;s Republic of Bulgaria concealed the smuggling trade carried out by the State Security through commercial enterprises and organizations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exemplary Home</title>
      <link>https://newdegeneration.xyz/work/exemplary-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 23:30:59 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://newdegeneration.xyz/work/exemplary-home/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Death Valley</title>
      <link>https://newdegeneration.xyz/work/shadow-valley/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 23:30:59 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://newdegeneration.xyz/work/shadow-valley/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Humor is the politeness of despair</title>
      <link>https://newdegeneration.xyz/work/destructive-sensuality/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://newdegeneration.xyz/work/destructive-sensuality/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Humor is the politeness of despair&amp;rdquo; in a meditaion on how the demonically possed inhrent strange channel switching powers and compulsions. Technically the piece is a video collage investigating the specifics of commercial video codec degradation. Based on key moments in Bulgaria’s visual subconscious, it uses various methods of controlled image destruction and degradation based on structural compression in videos. It is part of the &amp;ldquo;Destructive Sensuality&amp;rdquo; an exhibition by Sofia Dimova and Nikola Stoyanov, where the two artists romanticize the destructive dynamics of sensual experiences that imperceptibly become part of our everyday lives.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grey Zone/Dispositive</title>
      <link>https://newdegeneration.xyz/work/grey-zone/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 23:30:59 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://newdegeneration.xyz/work/grey-zone/</guid>
      <description>The city - transfigured into a gray zone emptied of people, of lights, immersed under water or discarded in the wild cosmos, folded beyond practicality, it represents a capsule emptied of its nature, emptied of its structures of power, emptied of its social bodies. A dispositive without practice, without knowledge and expertise, withoout our institutions and without time - a pure assemblage.&#xA;The project presents a virtual city-scape assembled out of distorted models of our familiar urban environment, rearanged into a non-euclidian vista.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Big MONUMENT of the Small Past</title>
      <link>https://newdegeneration.xyz/work/monument/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 23:30:59 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://newdegeneration.xyz/work/monument/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Allegorical Impulse</title>
      <link>https://newdegeneration.xyz/work/allegorical-impulse/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 23:30:59 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://newdegeneration.xyz/work/allegorical-impulse/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
