<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>solo on Nikola Stoyanov</title>
    <link>https://example.org/categories/solo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in solo on Nikola Stoyanov</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>av0id.biz@gmail.com (Nikola Stoyanov)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>av0id.biz@gmail.com (Nikola Stoyanov)</webMaster>
    <copyright>2023, Nikola Soyanov</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 12:21:30 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.org/categories/solo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Na gosho glavata</title>
      <link>https://example.org/work/test1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 12:21:30 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>av0id.biz@gmail.com (Nikola Stoyanov)</author>
      <guid>https://example.org/work/test1/</guid>
      <description>Markdown Cheat Sheet Thanks for visiting The Markdown Guide!
This Markdown cheat sheet provides a quick overview of all the Markdown syntax elements. It can’t cover every edge case, so if you need more information about any of these elements, refer to the reference guides for basic syntax and extended syntax.
Basic Syntax These are the elements outlined in John Gruber’s original design document. All Markdown applications support these elements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nature Morte</title>
      <link>https://example.org/work/nature-morte/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 12:04:30 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>av0id.biz@gmail.com (Nikola Stoyanov)</author>
      <guid>https://example.org/work/nature-morte/</guid>
      <description>NATURE MORTE is a multimediaproject that plants the philosoph-ical question in the ground - ona part of the country’s criticalinfrastructure, where access ishighly restricted. In an attempt tofind different approaches to reachthe excavation and its visualiza-tion, open data from satellite andgeological surveys and measure-ments were used, through whichthe digital topography of the mineswas built.Although the cosmic time ofgeoformation - the million-yearsuperimposition of layers thatproceeds in relative calm, whereseparate elements barely interact,there are also short periods ofruptures recorded in the layers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
