<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>collab on Nikola Stoyanov</title>
    <link>/en/categories/collab/</link>
    <description>Recent content in collab on Nikola Stoyanov</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Nikola Soyanov, 2023</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/en/categories/collab/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Postcards and Contraband</title>
      <link>/en/work/cards/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/work/cards/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Postcards and Contraband&amp;rdquo; begins by examining a work archive of the Bylgarian Customs Agency, Directorate for Combating Drug Trafficking from 1975-1985. The service notes, photographs, negatives, summaries and reports found mark part of the routine of the Customs Agency work, such as inspection and regulation of transit, but also the diplomatic image the Customs Agency must maintain to the international community.
The leading suspicion here is that the found archives give only a partial insight into the organized &amp;ldquo;hidden transit&amp;rdquo; - a term behind which the communist government of the People&amp;rsquo;s Republic of Bulgaria concealed the smuggling trade carried out by the State Security through commercial enterprises and organizations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grey Zone / Dispositive</title>
      <link>/en/work/grey-zone/grey-zone-dispositive/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/work/grey-zone/grey-zone-dispositive/</guid>
      <description>The city - transfigured into a gray zone emptied of people, of lights, immersed under water or discarded in the wild cosmos, folded beyond practicality, it represents a capsule emptied of its nature, emptied of its structures of power, emptied of its social bodies. A dispositive without practice, without knowledge and expertise, withoout our institutions and without time - a pure assemblage.
The project presents a virtual city-scape assembled out of distorted models of our familiar urban environment, rearanged into a non-euclidian vista.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
